<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="learningAnswerSpinner">
        <item>A greenhouse gas (GHG or GhG) is a gas that absorbs and emits radiant energy within the thermal infrared range, causing the greenhouse effect. These gases include carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), water vapor, nitrous oxide (N2O) and ozone (O3). Fluorinated gases are also considered to be greenhouse gases. Greenhouse gases act like a heat-trapping blanket, making the Earth habitable for humans. </item>
        <item>The Earth receives solar radiation from the sun. Passing through the atmosphere, some radiation is absorbed by the Earth, while some is reflected back to space. When the exchange of incoming and outgoing radiation occurs, some of the radiation becomes trapped by gases in the atmosphere. This creates a “greenhouse” effect and warms the planet.</item>
        <item>There are many ways to help fight climate change a few will be mentioned here, firstly divest from companies who uses fossil fuels so that they do not have a customer base to sell to. Another method is to learn the sciences behind climate change to understand how it works and how to stop it. Lastly it is important to advocate for governments who will help combat climate change as they have the most power allowing them to use their influence to tell the masses to fight climate change.</item>
        <item>The Paris Agreement is an international treaty on climate change. It aims to keep the overall increase in global temperatures below 2 degrees Celsius, with the hope of limiting it to 1.5 degrees Celsius.Scientists believe that these are the largest increases in global temperature that we could experience without causing catastrophic change to the Earth’s climate.</item>
        <item>Currently in the year 2022, China has the highest CO2 emissions, accounting for 28% of global carbon emissions. The United States ranks as the second top emitter at 15%, followed by Russia and then the United Kingdom.</item>
        <item>The biggest production of global emissions are by the Electricity and Heat Production sector with 25%, followed by Agriculture, Forestry, and Other Land Use at 24%, Industry with 21%, Transportation at 14% and finally Others at 10% global emissions.</item>
        <item>Currently in the year 2022, the warmest year to be recorded is a tie between 2016 and 2020 at awith the global average temperature 1.84 degrees Fahrenheit (1.02 degrees Celsius) warmer than the baseline 1951-1980 mean. The last seven years have been the warmest seven years on record.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>